Just follow this 49point onpage SEO
checklist and you'll get results like
this, this, and this. Let's dive right
in. Okay, so if you look on the right
hand side, this is going to be the
onpage SEO checklist. I'm going to be
walking you through, and you're going to
have access to this checklist below the
video. So, there'll be a link either in
the description or in the pinned
comments. So, let's just dive right into
it. So, number one, is the URL allowed
in the robots.ext file for Googlebot and
Bingbot? Okay. So, all we have to do is
just go to the page itself and just open
up the detailed Chrome extension and
then click on the robots.ext here. And
you can see as long as there's nothing
being blocked here by the disallow, then
you're going to be good to go. Okay? But
if you saw anything in here that like
any any bots are being blocked,
generally we don't want that to happen.
Okay? And especially we don't we we
don't want any of the traditional search
engines to be blocked and we also don't
want the AI crawlers to be blocked. So
if you see anything like GPT bot or
Google extended or perplexitybot, you
don't want any of that in there. Okay.
So this is this is the appropriate setup
here. This is this is going to be a pass
for them. Okay. So we can pass both of
these. And then the next thing here is
you want to see is the page actually
indexable? Like are there any directives
being used that would potentially be
blocking this page? Okay. So we're going
to go back over here once again detailed
Chrome extension. Go over to the robots
tag section. And if we see index follow,
that's perfectly fine. Also, if this is
completely blank, that's also okay.
Okay, so we can go over here. This is
passed. No worries there. And then, does
the page return a 200 status? 200 just
means that it's actually accessible.
It's not a 404 or it's being redirected
or there's some sort of server error.
Uh, that's what we want to see. Okay, so
we're going to go back over here, and
there's a little tool you can use, and
you'll see it here. Just run the URL
through this little tool, and it's
obviously in the checklist. and we just
want to see that it's actually showing
up as a 200 uh across all these
different uh areas that they ran this
test. Okay, so very simple. All right,
so this page is pretty much good to go.
Now the next one is can the page be
fetched directly? And we're looking at
chat GPT in this context. You could also
do this across any of the LLMs as well
because they do have the ability to do
direct retrieval, meaning when you put a
a domain or URL into chat GBT, it can
actually go and retrieve that directly.
Okay, so let's go ahead and grab this
URL here. And we're going to go into
chat GBT. And if you do the thinking
model typically the one I'm going to use
when I'm going to do any type of
retrieval and you can just do something
like you know tell me about this website
or actually you know we'll do more
specifically tell me about this page you
can actually look through the logic of
going through this. So it looks like
browsing page or key details uh it
actually did go through that that page
and then it scrolled. So, um, so based
on what we're seeing here, uh, you can
actually go and verify this, too, right?
If you want to make sure that it's
being, you know, not making things up
and it's not hallucinating, you can
actually go and verify these facts in
here. So, what you can do is just grab a
random piece of information like this
and just see if uh, hallucination has
been prevented. And you can see if we
search this, uh, this is actually legit,
which means the only way they would have
gotten this information is through uh,
retrieval. Okay? So, and just keep in
mind it can still hallucinate. So, just
be careful. always do some factchecking.
But what we're trying to do here is just
make sure like the purpose of this
little activity is just to see that chat
GBT can actually retrieve this page.
Okay, that's what we want to see. It can
actually go and it's not being blocked.
That's really what we want to see. All
right, so we can go and give that one a
pass. And then next we're going to see
is this page actually indexed in the
three search engines that matter the
most. Google, Bing, and Brave. Now,
here's why. Obviously, we want to we
want to be indexed in Google because
it's the number one search engine. Uh,
and it's also going to directly
influence Google's AI mode and it's
going to be influencing Google's Google
Gemini as well. Okay, so those two
products, if we're not indexed in
Google, we have basically no chance of
showing up uh in those products. Okay,
Bing, we know that we know that chat GBT
uses Bing and uh so does Perplexity. So,
we want to make sure that we're showing
up there as well when it I'm speaking in
reference to actually when it uses
retrieval. And then the third one is
Brave. and Brave. Uh there's some
evidence that Claude uses Brave as its
source of retrieval. So we just want to
make sure that we're indexable across
all these major search engines. That's
really important. Very easy. Just go and
do a site search. In fact, you don't
even have to do site. You could just
search the raw URL. And you just want to
see that it's popping up. Okay. So in
Google, we're good. When we do it in
Bing, we'll go over here. They're
actually indexed over here as well. And
then we look at Brave. They're indexed
here as well. Okay. So they're doing
well. They've they've got uh they've got
the proper foundation set up. Now, let's
dive into some of the other stuff. Is
the page HTML? Okay, so this is really
important. So, we know that the LLMs
prefer HTML. Okay, and if you're if your
page is if your page is built in
JavaScript, you're not going to you're
not going to be a good source of
retrieval uh for the LLM. So, just just
use HTML. Okay, I'm not going to get
super demon. Just use HTML. Make your
life e easier. Okay, it's quite simple.
If we go here and look at this view page
source, we can go ahead and just see,
you know, it is this actually HTML. The
answer is yes. But more importantly, we
want to see that the text is actually
crawable uh and retrievable in this
content. So, if you go past all this
like crazy uh code up here, we can see
we see actual meat in here, actual text
that's in the HTML, we can see that H1
popping up in here. We can see that H2.
And we can see these paragraph tags.
Okay, that's what you want to see. You
want to see that that text is actually
showing up right here in the code. Okay,
that's exactly what you want to see. So
that's a pass. Then uh is the core
content server rendered and visible in
the page source? Once again, this tells
you that it is being rendered. Okay, so
that kind of you pass both those checks
right away. Uh is a canonical URL set?
Just go right back in here. We're going
to go to the detail Chrome extension and
just see that it is a self-referencing
canonical tag. That's what you want to
see, right? Self-referencing. That's
exactly what you want. All right. Uh,
okay. So, we're good on all of these. We
They've passed everything so far. Okay.
So, does the page match the dominant
intent shown in the live SER for the
target keyword. Okay. So, basically what
we want to do is like we want to study
the the SERs and we want to see are we
actually matching what's in the SERs?
Like we don't want to reinvent the
wheel. Like there's a lot of things that
you can get fancy about and get uh
creative about, but one of the things
you don't want to do is when it comes to
intent, you want to copy the first page.
Okay? Don't ever try to go against that.
Uh unless you're very skilled, uh if
you're very skilled at this, you can,
but it's it's risky. Okay? What we want
to do is look at this and see, okay,
what is the general type of page that is
ranking? So when we look at the types of
pages that are ranking here, we see
we've got lots of lawyers who all have,
you know, really kind of commercial
pages. Okay, these are all just
commercial pages.
And, you know, obviously they there's
some room for improvement because
technically they function more
likeformational pages even though
they're commercial. But the the main
point is like mostly commercial pages.
Uh cool thing about inside of
Rankability here, if you click on view
SER, this will give you an unbiased view
of what the SERs look like right now.
Okay? And so you can actually go down
here and see what I like to do this
because I can actually determine like,
okay, what is a CTR going to look like?
And we see we've got a big ad block
here. So that's already going to hurt
CTR. Then we go down here. We've got a
local pack, meaning we have to focus on
the local pack number one above the
traditional search results. And then
we've got the And then we've got the
traditional search results here. Okay,
but we can see it's like 99.9%
commercial pages. So that tells us
everything we need to know. That means
we need to go and build a commercial
page as well. Now, based on what we're
seeing here, they've done that. Um,
obviously room for improvement, but in
general, they have they have matched the
intent to a certain extent. Okay. All
right. So, we're going to go and pass
them on that. Now, does the page include
elements needed to qualify for features?
Now, in this case,
if you look here on the competitors tab
on rankability, you can see any features
that exist. So, in this case, there
really aren't any features. The only
surf feature that we see major surf
feature is is the Google business
profiles the local pack here. So you
know that's kind of a separate
discussion alto together right but
there's no like people also ask or any
or there's not even actually an AI
overview in this case which is pretty
rare. So just one feature here and
obviously as long as they have a Google
business profile and they have an
address in Chicago and they're actively
require uh acquiring reviews that's like
80 to 90% of the equation. Okay. Does
the page display a visible publish date
and clearly labeled uh last update? And
is the content current reflected any
changes? So, this is really important
here, which is the LLMs tend to prefer
fresh pages that have been updated very
recently. So, this is it's important to
constantly be refreshing your pages and
making them up to date as much as
possible. Now, because this is a
commercial page, it's not likely to see
like a publish date or last updated. So,
what you can do is actually go into the
code and try to find the uh various
years that pop up in here. So, what I'll
do is I'll just do like 20 and then I'll
try to find anything that's going to
give us signals of how old this page
really is. Now, when we see this right
away, we see we found 2016. Okay, that's
not a good sign. All right, because what
that's telling us already is that this
page is very old. This page has not been
updated very often. Uh we've got 2023 in
here. We keep going down and more 2020
in here. So, we have we have we have
elements on this page that are go as far
back as 2016. Okay, that's really old.
All right, so that's going to be a big
fail here. Now, for commercial pages,
this is typically what you're going to
have to do because you're not going to
be able to see uh usually like a last
update or or publish it. Even then, even
on anformational page, you still want to
go through that same practice because
you want to see like is are there
outdated elements on this page and we
don't want to have that. We need to make
sure that it's extremely upto-date if we
want to have good performance. Okay, now
we're just talking about readability,
which is like having a TLDDR or
scannability, which is really important
for LLMs because they go and uh extract
through retrieval. They're pulling
elements and chunks from the page. So,
you want to make sure it's really really
clear what you guys do at like right
above the fold. Um, and the just the
general structure of this page, there's
a lot of room for improvement. Okay, so
I'm just going to go through a couple of
things here just because I I can't help
myself. So, couple of things here.
Number one, [snorts] this section up
here is very problematic because number
one, when you use this blue here, this
is the universal sign of a link and the
universal color of a link on the
internet. Okay? So, when you do when you
use this color here for text, it looks
like a link. Okay? And this here
actually is a link. So, we have text
that looks like a link that isn't a
link. And then we have an actual link
that's using the right color. So,
there's just some color issues here. And
then this one here is using actually a
different color for this link. So you
you want links to look like links, but
you want to make sure that the general
theme and and color scheme isn't going
to compete with those links. Okay? So
right now, this is not the appropriate
setup. In fact, I'd be moving away from
blue headings like this and I would move
to like, you know, maybe a darker blue
or even just black. Okay? That's just
much easier. And let and let links be
links. Uh, as far as that blue color,
another thing is too, the the phone
number is one of the most important
things on this page, yet it's very
muted, okay? It's a very muted color.
So, we want to make that I want to make
that phone number be the star of the
show because it's critical that we get
people actually call us to to actually
drive conversions. Okay? Uh, so that's
really important. And then right here,
you know, the general structure here
like uh UX 101 is that the primary
headline is above the fold. Okay? So,
there should be at any page that you're
on on a website, the the headline should
be one of the first things that you see
because it helps the user understand
where they are uh in that moment. Okay?
But right now, if we were to just kind
of like move this up, if someone landed
on this page, they'd have no idea where
they are. They don't know what this page
is. They don't know, you know, there's a
happy truck driver here, but we don't
really know what this page is about,
right? If you're just on this alone with
no context. So, you have to shift this
around. And what I would do is I would
use just like a left right format. So
you'd have headline on the left, uh, sub
headline, call to action, then maybe a
form over here too, and then like maybe
some testimonials. Like you could
restructure this page quite easily.
Okay. And right now it this page is not
really built for for maximum
conversions. So this is this is much
bigger than just an SEO content and an
on-page SEO issue. There's there's like
full-on structural issues going on here
with this page. Um, if you want some
like a good in inspo, I would use Look
at these guys here. Okay, I've I've
talked about them before. Uh, this is
not my client or anything. I just think
that one of my favorite websites I've
seen on the local level. It's beautiful.
Does so many things well and um just
just model this, okay? Because you got a
beautiful phone number above the fold,
very prominent. You've got another CTA
here for people that are not ready to
call. And then you see the CTAs
throughout, right? the calls to action.
We got a [clears throat] nice beautiful
format like I said left right format. So
we got a nice left left here with the
context and then we've got the call to
action. So and then obviously we've got
some social proof. It's just overall
this is you it doesn't get much better
than this. This is about as good as it
gets. Okay. So model this. This is what
a beautiful conversion focused design
will look like. And you can still get
maximum SEO benefits uh by do in fact
you'll get more SEO benefits by doing
this because you're going to get the
goal completions that are are supposed
to happen on your page which is likely
also a Google ranking factor. Okay. So I
would go ahead and give this one a fail
on that. Uh if applicable does a page
include a short verdict box? The answer
is no. This is like very textheavy.
uh most people are never going to read
this and this is really just an attempt
to manipulate Google but not necessarily
uh drive conversions which that should
be the number one objective. The number
one objective should not be how do we
manipulate Google to rank and how do I
manipulate the uh AI platforms. The goal
should be how do we drive maximum goal
completions on this page considering
this is a transactional page. That's the
number one objective. Then the SEO is
second to that. Okay. So we're going to
give that a fail. Uh, does a page
provide information gain compared to the
top results? Probably not. Okay, we can
we don't have to do much analysis there.
Okay. Is the word count sufficient to
satisfy search intent without necess
unnecessary padding? I'm going to go
ahead and say no, but just because we'll
go ahead and take you get some
quantifiable proof here. We can see uh
we we actually placed all the content
here. So if you do a uh content
optimizer here, you can actually extract
even if and if you don't, you can
actually go over here to URL extraction
and then it will in will go ahead and
retrieve that information, bring it back
uh into this editor. [clears throat] But
right here in the word count, word count
is not a ranking factor per se. Um but
we we want to be within range as to
where the competitors are, but we don't
want to be super aggressive there. And
so in the context is we're using median
word count. So we're eliminating the
outliers. So like some some competitor
has, you know, I don't know, 10,000
words and some competitors got 50. We're
just eliminating them all together and
bringing to that true middle. So this
optimal range is like you want to be in
here. In fact, I would argue you'd want
to be more on the low end because if
you're on the low end, you're going to
practice brevity. You're going to focus
on conversions. Um, and you're not going
to just fluff up your content, which is
not beneficial really. So, we're looking
at 4,300 words. If I was working on this
page, I'd delete
nearly 3,000 of the words on this page.
Like, I would literally just just chop
away at it. And I'll show you how we can
restructure this page. But, in general,
this target word count is critical
because, you know, it word count's a
tricky thing because just having words
is not a ranking factor, but you need
words to have context, right? like the
uh search engine crawlers and LLMs, they
need meat. They need actual words to
understand what the page is about. So,
in that way, you could argue that it is
a factor. Uh but it's not like a
specific word count is a fact. It's not
like the LM say, oh, this page has 1500
words, therefore it's going to rank
better. That's not what it that's not
what it is. It's more that, oh, this
page has something that I can
understand, and then I know what I can
do with this, right? And that's really
what it is. It's it's it's the
substance. It's not the quantity. Okay.
All right. So, we're going to go and uh
that one's going to be a fail. And then
uh you know, basic grammar and spelling.
Actually kind of cool. Most people don't
know like some of the functions in here,
but you can actually go in here and
click on AI.
And what this will do is if you just
click on spelling and grammar, this will
just do a full spelling and grammar
analysis uh with with our AI. Um, so
there's like some little features in
here that I don't really talk about, but
this is a quick way you can do this. Is
it means you don't even need Grammarly
to be honest. I canceled Grammarly like
a year and a half ago. So, uh, all
right. So, is the are the headings, uh,
hierarchy logical with short paragraphs,
list tables. Okay. So, going back to
here, we can see, uh, there there's a
bunch of grammatical errors and
opportunities to improve uh, this
overall. So, if [clears throat] you just
do accept and replace, it will actually
just clean all of this up automatically
for you. Okay. Okay. So, if you want to
do a quick analysis of the headings,
just go over to the brief here and then
click on outline. And you can see the
heading structure all set up here. So,
this is actual headings pulled from that
page. And we can see this is this is not
exactly what we want. Uh we want to make
sure that we've got like, you know, a
solid H1, which is good. This is
perfect. Got a good H1. Then we would
have an H2, but then within that H2, we
would start to layer in, you know, H3s.
Um, so this is just a little H2 heavy.
We don't want it to be like this. So
like if you look at this competitor
here, they've got a nice setup. They got
H1, H2, then they've got the H3s within
that H2 and so on and so forth. This is
a good setup. This is uh a little too H2
heavy. Okay, moving on to loading speed.
Just run the page through Google Page
Speed Insights and you can see check on
mobile and check on desktop. So they're
about a 57 on mobile and they're 98 on
desktop. Knowing that most of their
traffic is likely mobile, then this is a
problem. Okay. Um, for B2B, desktop
tends to be the much more prevalent, but
for, you know, BTOC type of situation
like this, you're going to see a lot
more mobile traffic. So, this is
definitely something we're going to want
to fix. Okay. Uh, is it mobile friendly?
All right. There's a very simple thing
you could do here. If you want to check
to see mobile friendliness, just go
ahead and like open up the URL like this
and just condense this down. And this
will give you a pretty rough idea of
what it's going to look like on mobile.
Okay? It's not perfect, but it gives you
a pretty good idea. The the only true
way to do this is just literally pick up
your phone and and look on your actual
device. Okay, that's the best way to
really do it. All right, but this one
looks good on that front. Pass. And then
is the reading level appropriate for the
target audience in general online? Like
any internet level content should be
very simple, like very very simple
content, easy to understand, easy to
read. And what we'll see here if we go
over here to the readability, uh this is
a college level content even up to
college graduate. This is way too way
too intense. And so this is one of the
biggest issues I see with lawyers. They
always have really really technical
content and but their clients are not
highly technical in the legal space. So
you have to convert this to something
they can actually understand. Okay, this
is not what we want. We want it to be
much lower high school, elementary, like
as low as we can go. Uh first grade
level, you know, try to go to that
level. that's going to make a big
difference uh as far as conversion rates
on the internet. Okay, now we're talking
about some basic onpage SEO 101 which is
really just about keyword placement and
then of course uh overall topic
coverage. So what you can do is go to
the brief here and you can actually
click on this and we actually have it
built in here. So you can see uh the
primary keyword you want to see that
primary keyword is actually popping up
in the URL. So this did not pass. So
this is going to be a fail. And when I
say primary keyword I mean Chicago truck
accident lawyer. So, we don't see
Chicago in here at all. And my my test
for this is what I do is like I pretend
there is no context. So, just looking at
this page, we see practice area truck
accidents. I don't know where that is,
right? I don't know if that's Chicago. I
don't know if that's Florida. You know,
it there's no context. So, you need to
have the city to give context. That's
just my personal opinion. All right.
This one here is about title tag. They
passed that. They're good to go. Uh
we'll look at the metad description.
Metad description looks good. Uh,
actually, sorry, pass that one. Pass
that. Uh, there is a keyword in the H1.
Yes, we know that. Is the keyword in the
first 100 words? Uh, we can go ahead and
look in here. Yeah, I mean, I would say
that I'll give that one a pass. That
that's fair. Um, variation in the H2.
Uh, yeah. Yeah, we go to give that one a
pass. Descriptive headings overall.
Okay. I'm not going to be too gruff on
that. And then this one, although it is
the last point, is the most important
point in this section, which is does it
cover all the relevant topics. Okay, so
go over here. You look at relevance, but
we're actually going to go to unused,
and we're going to see we've got tons of
unused topics that the competitors are
using. Okay, so I would argue that this
page needs to be completely redone.
Like, and so, you know, we passed all
those things, but the reality is if this
was my client, this page I would just
start from scratch. Okay? And the way I
would do it is pretty simple. I would
just start with AI as the base using AI
to build that base content and then use
the human editorial process to make it
better. Okay? So go into here, you use
the AI writer inside of rankability if
you wanted to. Uh and what I do in this
section is obviously pick service page
because it's a commercial page. And then
what I'll do is I'll use chat GBT to go
and give me context. Okay? So right here
you can see you can use this little
prompt but basically we can go and
retrieve that information. It will go
and give us context about that brand.
And then this is how we can make that AI
content uh a lot more unique relative to
the people that are ranking because a
commercial page is really easy to
actually make unique because it should
be about your brand and there is only
you. So it's automatically unique out of
the gate. So what you can do though is
like I'll have it turn into a markdown
file and then we'll just copy this over.
We'll put this into the context window
and then I will generate that content.
And then in the last section under goal
completions, this is really really
important. So what I recommend doing is
just making sure that all of their calls
to action actually work. Okay? And I
already said that you like this page I I
would personally this should be
redesigned in my opinion, but let's just
say they were to keep this. I want to
make sure that the phone number is
actually clickable. So like if I click
on this, will it actually call? The
answer is yes. Okay, so it actually does
work. But then we want to do is actually
want to test this form. So you can use a
service like Mailinator. Just do this
real quickly. and I want to see if this
form actually works because if it
doesn't work then that's going to cause
a lot of problems. All right, so we're
gonna run this through use mailinator
and I apologize uh to this brand that
I'm doing this but just for the sake of
for the argument here it seems to have
worked. I would go ahead and say that uh
this is a solid pass. However, I would
argue that this is an area this is where
now we're starting to step outside of
the SEO realm here. But as far as
conversion rate optimization, as far as
building trust leading up to a call, all
of those things, what you want to do is
build in a proper funnel. So what we're
seeing here is like, okay, you contact
them. What happens next? Okay, going to
get in touch with you shortly. Okay, so
it just kind of leaves the user up, you
know, you don't really know what's going
to happen after this. Am I get are they
going to get in touch with me? I'm not
sure. Right? So if you're trying to win
deals, you want to be the one that's
controlling that sales environment. So,
what I would do personally is soon as
someone submits this form, I'd send them
to a thank you page. On the thank you
page, it would be a video of one of the
lawyers, and I would say, "Hey, thank
you so much for uh, you know, submitting
your free case review. Here's what's
going to happen next. Uh, here's what
you can expect." And you you set those
expectations for them, right? And then
even maybe give them some additional
resources that they can use. Even maybe
show some uh some social proof, some
case studies, or even uh outcomes that
you've gotten for your clients. So
you're building trust like right there.
So now they feel like, okay, I
understand the process. I'm good to go.
Uh but this is like basically, you know,
and this happens a lot with with legal
based websites. Uh actually happens a
lot with basically every local business
I've seen. Um but we need to actually
continue that process because you you
don't just want to have this form
submission then nothing happens after.
You want to continue to build that trust
and get get that prospect to know, like,
and trust you. This deal has not been
closed, right? you got to you have to
continually sell to to close that deal.
And then also when we go into the inbox,
we see that there is actually no
confirmation email that has even come
through from that contact submission. So
once again, we've got two things that
have to happen. Number one is when
someone submits a form, they go to a
thank you page, they they know what's
coming next. Number two, they get an
email confirmation about that contact
submission. Okay, so very basic stuff.
I'm not talking about like complex
funnels here, which we could talk about,
but I'm just saying that's like just the
basic that every business should be
doing in the context of uh anyone that
has a lead generation focused business.
So, we can see that the AI content is
already done. We'll go ahead and click
through. So, this is going to be very
good to show the distinct difference
between this draft versus the other one.
On the right hand side here, they
they're missing a lot of kind of core
topics in here. Okay, a lot of those
really important topics. With this
draft, we can see we've covered
basically all the important topics.
Okay? That's why it's scored so well
because it's covering what it needs to
cover, right? But also, as I mentioned
earlier, when you can see like the the
really juiced up word count. So, you can
see here only about 1,400 words. Okay?
So, we've chopped that word count down
dramatically. Um, and it it's already in
a much better place. Now, I would say
that the readability is still a little
it's a little strong. It's a little
strong. So the AI went a little went a
little too college graduate in this
case. So I would this is where the human
edits come in. I would start to kind of
simplify this a little bit more. This is
where you need a human. Okay. But this
in general, this is what you want to
see. You want to have it be lean and
highly relevant and personalized and
also obviously have that good
readability. So this is what this is
what a good draft looks like. Now I've
said this a million times at this point.
This is a draft. This is just the first
draft. Uh for us, you know, like I said,
this took, you know, less than five
minutes to make this draft. We'll then
spend an hour, maybe up to two hours, uh
with a human going through reworking
this, make sure it's going to flow well
on that commercial page and all of that
stuff. Okay? So, this is like all that
time that you save from the writing,
reinvest it into the back end of that
content production process or that
editorial process. And that's going to
ensure that your content does much
better uh and you're and you're you're
practicing proper on-page SEO. Okay. And
the last point of today, I just want to
make sure that it's clear that when it
comes to on-page SEO, it is only one
sliver of the total equation as far as
performance in Google and ChatGBT and
LLM. Okay. What what really matters like
and this this is unfortunately people
think that like if they just focus on
site, they're going to get good results.
And unless you're in a really
uncompetitive industry, it's not going
to be the case. you still need to carve
out all of these other elements. So,
I'll have a video uh that you can watch
next that's going to show you how to do
chat GBT SEO specifically. Uh and
there'll be other videos on my channel
also about how to how to optimize for
Google as well. But you'll see that like
there's much more to this equation in
particular uh offsite, okay? And you can
see your backlink profile and your third
party. And by the way, this chart is
just my personal opinion of like impact
of these these particular categories,
but 50% in my opinion at least, I'm
being maybe a little uh conservative
here, is what's happening off of your
website. That's where most of the impact
is going to come from is what's
happening off of your website, not what
you're doing on your site. Uh that's
only equates you maybe 50% of the total
equation. So, just wanted to show you
this to make sure we're, you know, we're
being realistic that even if you follow
this checklist and there's a lot of
content stuff on there as well, we're
only looking about, you know, maybe 25%
a quarter of the equation. So, make sure
you're covering all of these different
areas if you want to maximize your AI
search uh and SEO performance.